let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "   Who invented Java Programming?",
    answer: "James Gosling",
    options: [
        " Bjarne Stroustrup",
        "Dennis Ritchie",
        "James Gosling",
        "Guido van Rossum",
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "Which statement is true about Java?",
    answer: "Java is a platform-independent programming language",
    options: [
     "Java is a platform-independent programming language",
     "Java is a platform-dependent programming language",
     "ava is a code dependent programming language",
    "Java is a sequence-dependent programming language"
      
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
    answer: "JDK",
    options: [
      " JRE  ",
      "JIT",
       "JDK",
      " JVM"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Which one of the following is not a Java feature?",
    answer: "Use of pointers",
    options: [
      "Object-oriented",
      "Use of pointers",
      "Portable",
     "Dynamic and Extensible"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: " Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java?",
    answer: "  keyword",
    options: [
     " identifier & keyword ",
"identifier",
"keyword",
"none of the mentioned"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "What is the extension of java code files?",
    answer: ".java",
    options: [
      ".js",
      ".txt",
      ".class",
      ".java"
    ]
},
{
 numb: 7, 
    question: "Which environment variable is used to set the java path?",
    answer:   " JAVA_HOME",
    options:[
      " MAVEN_Path",
      " JavaPATH",
      " JAVA",
      " JAVA_HOME"
    ]
},

{
  numb: 8,
  question: "Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?",   
  answer:   "Compilation",
  options:[
    "Encapsulation",
"Compilation",
"Inheritance",
"Polymorphism"
  ]
},
{
  numb: 9,
    question: "Which of the following is a type of polymorphism in Java Programming?",
    answer: "Compile time polymorphism",
    options:[
      "Execution time polymorphism",
      "Multilevel polymorphism",
      "Compile time polymorphism",
      "Multiple polymorphism"
   
    ]
},
{
  numb: 10,
   question: "What is Truncation in Java?",
   answer: " Floating-point value assigned to an integer type",
   options:[
    "Floating-point value assigned to a Floating type",
"Integer value assigned to floating type",
" Integer value assigned to floating type",
"Floating-point value assigned to an integer type"
]

},

];